Guide to the Provost Charles Peake Administrative Records, 1967-1971 UA.3.1.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Education - Department of Higher Education, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Proposals for fellowships in Community College Administration, 1969; correspondence on proposed institute in higher education, 1970; proposed program in educational psychology, 1970; correspondence on cooperative program with Seoul Korea University, 1970.
- Education, School of, January-June 1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Memos on cooperative project with Penn State and Temple to prepare teachers; memos on work being done in various departments of School of Education; a proposal for development of a partnership in urban education, 1968; triplet program-training of teachers; certificate program in dentistry for the exceptional child; papers in H.E.W. grant on elementary and secondary supervision policy relating to student teaching/internships in case of strikes etc.; press release on leisure-learn program; correspondence and statement on vocational rehabitation personnel needs; memo on support for the teachers corps. in Pittsburgh.
- Education, School of, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Memo on correspondence on urban teacher education; correspondence on program to help the community in the field of education; guidelines on faculty, staff, student recruitment; correspondence on development of various programs in the schools; news release on inaugurating operation Head-Start program to give Head Start workers college training; memo on facilities requirements for Department of Educational Communication, 1969; memo on the responsibilities of office of undergraduate study.
- Education, School of - Individualized Instruction, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Engineering - Graduate Program with Corps. of Engineers, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Engineering, School of, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Correspondence about Gwilym Price lecture series, 1969-1970; lectures: Philip Sporn, "Engineering and the University in the World of Today and Tomorrow," November 20, 1968, and Augustus Kinzel, "Engineering and our way of life," May 7, 1968; Proposal for formal faculty organization; Report on Dean Hoelscher's trip to India and South East Asia, 1970; correspondence relating to school administration.
- Engineering, School of - Special Projects and Programs, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  Ten year planning report, 1968; establishing engineering services division; new program leading to Dr. of Engineering, 1969; proposed Biomedical Engineering Program, 1969; proposal for a computer facility in Benedum Hall, 1968.
- Engineering, School of, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Memos on tailoring math courses for engineering students; news release on Alcoa professorships; paper on new undergraduate program, July 1967; statements on operations and development plans; analysis of SAT scores at Oakland and regional campuses; list of Mellon grants to aid Pitt; paper by Dr. Hoelscher on a national engineering information network; proposal for PhD Program in Civil Engineering; policy memoranda; miscellaneous correspondence on School's operation.
- Engineering, School of, July-December 1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  News release – 2 week institute for high school students; papers by Dr. Hoelscher "The Genesis of Strain in American Universities" and "The Terminology Quandary in Technical Education"; photo of Alcoa representative giving check to Chancellor with Dr. Hoelscher and Provost present, October 28, 1968; memos on school administration.
- Engineering, School of - International Conference, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Memos on planning, program and papers for international conference on "Interdisciplinary Aspects of the Application of Engineering Technology to the Industrialization of developing Countries" held October 20-25, 1968, sponsored by Engineering School and Center for International Studies.
- Engineering, School of, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Papers by Dr. Hoelscher – "Technology and Social Changes," "Education by Degrees," and "Industrialization of Developing Countries…"; proposed policy statement on Engineering School Judicial Board; curriculum vitae on Dr. Hoelscher; memo on responsibilities of the dean; proposal for support of creative design program; paper by Minor Hawks, "How can an urban university meet the needs for continuing engineering students?"; statistics on Engineering Students; memos on school administration.
- Engineering, School of, January-June 1968 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Series of announcements and reports instituted to keep faculty informed; memos on upgrading regional campus engineering curriculum; 3-2 year program in liberal arts/engineering discontinued, 1968; letters about Gulf gift for new building; correspondence on termination of a navy contract; report on use of Beviar fund; announcement of Engineering Service Division; memo on University of Santa Maria, Chile; memos about school's operation.
- English Department, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  News release on great lectures; memos on publications by faculty; memos on space/equipment problems; memo on realistic way to achieve social justice; Report on "Personnel Crisis in the English Department," and critique, 1969; memo on recognition of Professor Crow; miscellaneous memos on departmental affairs; proposal for Professor Exchange Program – exchanging faculty with Black Colleges in the South, 1969.
- English Department (Box 12, Folder 5)
- English Department - Peterson, Pittsburgh Plan, Project Plan, Writer's Conference (Box 12, Folder 6)
- English Department - Report on Library Needs (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Environmental Studies - Undergraduate and Master's program, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  Survey of environmental programs and U.S. colleges by Conservation Foundation 1968; proposal from dean of School of Education for interdisciplinary graduate program.
- "F" General Correspondence File (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Faculty of Arts and Sciences, November 1967-June 1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Correspondence about establishing Faculty Arts and Science (FAS), Fall 1967; correspondence about GSPIA Professor Coffey's proposal, November 1967; general correspondence on FAS policies and issues; memo on proposed building plans for Arts and Sciences, 1968; memo on sabbatical leave policy, 1968; correspondence on cost of small classes, February 1968; memos on FAS budgets; FAS statement of objectives, May 15, 1968.
- Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Dean Search Committee, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Memos from the Dean and faculty recommending changes in Dean's office.
- Faculty Arts and Sciences, July-December 1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Correspondence on administration of FAS; Dean's memos on FAS; review and analysis of graduate programs in FAS, 1969; correspondence and draft of FAS Bylaws, 1969; faculty salary survey; Dr. Halliday request to resign as Dean, March 14, 1969, and details of farewell party; Black admission proposal, 1969; memo on faculty overloads; memo on faculty with pending PhD, 1969; letter about Rosenberg being appointed FAS Dean, October 9,1969; memo on graduate teaching assistant problems with compensation/teaching loads, 1969; budget making policy; memo requesting Crystallography Lab become department, 1969.
- Faculty Research Fund Proposal, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Position papers on establishing a research fund for the faculty in Social Sciences and Humanities, 1968.
- Falk School, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Thank you to Mrs. Leon Falk for $5000 grant; memo about tuition; memo on dorm proposed on Falk playgroundsite, 1969.
- Finance, Professions, Planning, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Report on Student Housing and future real estate strategy by Vice Chancellor with Dr. Peake's comments, 1969; Reorganization of Office of Finance, 1968 and 1970; note on mortgages; memo on change of fiscal year, 1966; miscellaneous operational memos; memos on the Vice Chancellor of Professions' Draft of Professional Schools policy, 1958; Professions – Disciplines relations, 1960; Report by Daniel Rathbun on planning, allocation of funds, 1969; Report on Personal Family and Children's Center, 1968.
- Fine Arts Department, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Correspondence on security of Lochoff frescoes; correspondence about development of University Art Gallery; memos and attached article on Japanese art by Fine Arts student Howard Link.
- Fine Arts Department - Leff Collection Exhibit Catalog and Photographs, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Fine Arts Department, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  News release on art exhibits and visiting professors; memo on cooperation with School of Education; memo on department administration and faculty; plans for Mellon Seminar in Europe, 1969; memo about department allocations in Arts and Sciences; description of course in "History of Cities"; financial needs of the library; correspondence on exhibit of Reginald Marsh painting; correspondence about appointment of Thomas Lacey in Fine Arts; correspondence on Frick endowment fund; correspondence about search for Department Chairman, 1968.
- Foreign Language Instruction, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Enrollment statistics; paper on language teaching at Pitt; proposal for reorganization of language teaching; paper-place of language in liberal arts curriculum; rescinding foreign language requirement for PhD program in Pharmacy; ERIC report on foreign language teaching by Pitt authors.
- French and Italian (Box 13, Folder 11)
- French and Italian Language and Literature, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Proposal for M.A. program in Italian, 1968; memo on use of faculty club by teaching assistants; miscellaneous correspondence.
- French and Italian - Rouen Program, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- General Studies, School of, 1968-1970 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Proposal policy for staffing and policy statement; policy committee meeting minutes and memos; memos on special courses; classes for hospital nursing students; pre-college program; proposed B.S. of General Studies degree; proposal for continuing the learning counseling in School of General Studies, 1970; General Studies Board of Visitors meeting agenda and papers, December 1968; news releases on courses.
- General Studies - Student Aid for Minorities, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Memo concerning financial aid for black students, 1970; appointment of Thomas Sawyer to administer program.
- General Studies, School of, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  5 and 10 year projection plans, 1968; organization of school, 1970; proposal for Continuing Education Program and related correspondence, 1970; Report of School of General Studies Review Committee, 1970.
- General Studies, School of, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Bylaws of General Studies, 1970; memos on School's Council; Bylaws of General Studies Cabinet, 1970; related memos; report on student concerns.
- General Studies, School of (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Memos on staff problems and needs; memo on changing General Studies Council; Bylaws of Faculty Arts and Sciences; memo by Chancellor on problems, 1969; problem with connection with Faculty Arts and Science; Council minutes May 28, 1969; Revision of General Studies By-Laws.
- Geography and Demography - Proposed Department, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Geography (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Geology - Bermuda (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Germanic Language and Literature, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Correspondence on administration of Department and annual reports, 1967-1969.
- German (Box 14, Folder 9)
- German - Institute for Basic German (IBG) (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Graduate and Professional Council (Dr. Peake, Chairman), 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Graduate Study, University Council, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Review of Graduate programs; statistics in graduate study at Pitt; memos on reorganization of graduate study; minutes of graduate council meetings; charts showing reorganization of graduate study, 1958-1970.
- Graduate Study, University Council, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  "Activities in the Area of Graduate Study" report, 1968-1969; Proposed reorganization of Graduate Study, November 1969; meeting minutes of Council 1968-1970; proposed Dr. of Engineering program, 1969.
- Graduate Study, University Council, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Memos on certificate in Philosophy, 1970; proposal on intermediate degree, 1969; policy on administration of interdisciplinary graduate programs, 1970; proposals for new graduate programs, 1970; reclassification of members of graduate faculty.
- Graduate Study, University Council, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Memos and proposals on graduate study; roster of graduate faculty, 1968; organization of graduate faculty, 1968; proposed change in foreign language requirement for PhD; memos on post doctoral fellowships.
- Graduate Study (Box 15, Folder 5)
  New regulations for PhD; proposed graduate school of arts and sciences; related correspondence.
- Graduate Study Funding, 1961-1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  Annual reports on NASA training grant, 1966-1968; reorganization, 1970; correspondence on NDEA Title VI Fellowships Counterpart funds, 1961-1970; foreign language requirement correspondence; correspondence with Congress about Title VI funds, 1968; New faculty and TA needs 1969/1970; correspondence from schools and departments on graduate study.
- Grant, Title VI Higher Education Grant to Support Undergraduate Education, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Grants - HUD Grant on Urban Transportation, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Grant no. PA-R11-8-69 for program of research and teaching in urban transportation interdisciplinary; includes proposal, progress reports, and correspondence.
- Grants - HUD Grant on Urban Transportation, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Memos on task force to handle interdisciplinary grant proposal, 1968; Budget allocations; administration plans; C. Peake, principal investigator.
- Grants - HUD Grant on Urban Transportation, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  Research and training proposal, 1970; proposed projects submitted by faculty members from Engineering, Geography, Public Health, Business.
- Grants - HUD Grant on Urban Transportation, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  Correspondence relating to grant re administration and planning; vitae of faculty submitting projects under grant.
- Grants - Urban Mass Transportation Administration Grant, 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Memos on UMTA proposal and grant no. URT 50, W.L. Garrison, School of Engineering, project director, including budget and working papers.
- Greensburg Campus, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Correspondence on operations, 1968-1970; policy guidelines and 10 year objectives; financial statements.
- Guatemala Project, 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Report of visit to San Carlos by Joseph Buckley, Pharmacy; progress reports; T. Dunkelberger, chief officer at San Carlos; papers on development and research; program development in El Salvador; cooperative research program in chemistry and pharmacy program in biology; funding from A.I.D. cut.
- Guatemala Project, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Terminal report on project, "Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala Facultad de Odontologia" 1962-66 report on School of Odontology, San Carlos; two clippings of Dr. Peake's visit to San Carlos, 1967.
- "H" General File, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Correspondence re trip to event by Post Gazette editor Frank Hawkins and letters of introduction to various faculty in several countries; correspondence re Norwell Harrigan of Caribbean Research Institute concerning an appointment at Pitt, includes institute publications.
- Health Law Center/Aspen Corp., 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Agreement with Aspen Corp. to provide automated retrieval of legal references.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor - School of Pharmacy, 1968-1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Memo on deleting undergraduate program in pharmacy, 1968; research proposal to Kellogg Foundation for collaborative research with Central American University, 1969; news release and correspondence; Bulletin 1968-1969.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor (Box 17, Folder 6)
  University wide program in environmental health, 1968; proposal for joint program of GSPIA for PhD; letter to Pennsylvania governor on water pollution conference, 1969; Resume of meeting on proposing a center for development of international health projects, 1969; memos on operation of school.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor - School of Health Related Professions, 1967-1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Report of study on Allied Health Professions, 1969; correspondence about establishing school.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor, 1967-1970 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Proposed program for training medical records librarians at Pitt, 1967; proposal for degree program in basic sciences, 1968; correspondence.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor (Box 17, Folder 9)
  Memo on awarding PhD in Bioacoustics; memo to Chancellor from Dean on status of medical education, 1968; news release on appointments; operational memos.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor - Nursing School, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  Minutes of meeting on admission and curriculum problems, 1968; memo on data on nursing schools in U.S.; memo on Master's degree in Nursing; description of Nursing Program at Pitt; papers presented at conference of National League for Nursing, 1969; correspondence about administration of Nursing School.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor - Dental Medicine School, 1964-1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Memos on granting DMD degree retroactive; memo on new curriculum, 1969; memos and news releases on administration.
- Health Professions, Vice Chancellor - Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic (WPIC) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  News release; staff meeting minutes and correspondence, 1969-1970; progress report for Maurice Falk – WPIC Social/Community Psychiatry/ Behavioral Science Curriculum Development Program, 1967-1968.
- Hill District Project - Dr. O.K. Moore, 1967-1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  Proposal for LRDC Learning Project in a Hill District School; two articles by Dr. Moore on "Responsive Environments."
- Hispanic Languages Department (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Hispanic analysis, 1969; proposed Mellon professor; letter to Chancellor by Chairman on "Bureaucratic lethargy"; letter from Dr. Cardona about accomplishments on Sabbatical; department correspondence.
- History and Philosophy of Science, 1965-1970 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Proposal to establish History of Science program; description of University of Cambridge History Science Program; draft of a program for public school teachers, 1966; paper on program for History and Philosophy of Science, 1969; Budget for program, 1970; related correspondence.
- History Department, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  Memos about faculty promotions; visiting professors; annual report Archives Industrial Society, 1969; correspondence on Historical Methods Newsletter.
- History Department - Industrial Society Program (Box 18, Folder 7)
- History Department - Kofsky-Allen Affair, Center for Election Data, Labor Management Relations Center (Box 18, Folder 8)
- History Department - Oral History Program, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  Proposal for Stanton Balfour oral history program on Pittsburgh Renaissance, 1970; conference proceedings for Pittsburgh Oral history, 1968.
- Hong Kong, 1966-1968 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, proposal and reports on cooperative programs with Chinese University of Hong Kong.
- Hong Kong Cooperative Program, Correspondence with Vice Chancellor (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Correspondence with Dr. Choh-Ming Li, Vice Chancellor, Chinese University of Hong Kong including arrangements for his visit to Pitt, 1967; correspondence about visit of Premier C.K. Yang of Republic of China to U.S. (unable to visit Pitt), 1967.
- Hong Kong Cooperative Program, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  Proposal for continuing program, 1969; Report on Sociology program, 1967; Correspondence with C.K. Yang 1967-1970.
- Hong Kong Cooperative Program - Sociology Department (Box 19, Folder 3)
  Correspondence about Professor M. Berkowitz sent from Pitt to head Sociology department at Chinese University of Hong Kong, 1967-1969; problems with his criticizing the Chinese University covered in Hong Kong press.
- Hong Kong University - Faculty Exchange, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Hong Kong University - Personal Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Honorary Degree Candidates, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Honorary Degrees, 1964-1970 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Procedures for selection, 1969-1970; correspondence; speech made honoring L.P. Snow, 1964; list of prospective honorees, 1965; citations for Frank Magee, Alan Waterman, Lawrence Mumford, and Felipe Herroro Lane.
- Housing, Graduate Students, 1967-1970 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Reports from various deans on urgent need for graduate student housing.
- Human Services Research Proposal, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Human Subjects in Experiments Policy, 1966-1969 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- IBM Graduate Fellowships, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program in Information Science - Report, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Instructional Experimentation Division, 1967-1970 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  Preliminary studies for curricular innovation, 1967; paper-computer systems for guidance; correspondence with Steele Ison and acceptance of position of associate provost for instructional experimentation, 1968.
- Instructional Experimentation Division, 1968-1970 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  Prospectus for personalized higher education model from Steele Gow at Bucknell University; prospectus for development of instructional experimentation at Pitt plus preliminary drafts, 1968; organization charts; prospectus for course distribution study; Gow's testimony in Pennsylvania House of Representatives on master plan for higher education in Pennsylvania; vitae of prospective faculty member for division (he declined offer); memos on merit scholarship, 1970; summary of Division activities, 1969; proposal for dividing college of Arts and Sciences into three colleges, 1970.
- International Dimension Reorganization - University Center for International Studies, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Report of Chancellor's committee on reorganization 1967-1968; minutes and drafts for reorganization; inter-institutional cooperation, 1968; Development and Research – University of San Carlos; proposed center for international studies, 1968; establishment of center, 1968.
- International Dimensions - Ford Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  Annual report on Foundation on International Activities at University and related correspondence; International Dimension Committee Minutes.
- International Studies Program Awards, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  Statement of committee's responsibilities for awarding money to faculty for scholarship projects; requests for awards with brief description of projects; letters granting awards.
- International Studies Proposals, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Proposal for an information system for updating, retrieval and analysis of data on Communist political leaders in Eastern Europe, 1968; proposal on inter-institutional cooperation, 1968; proposals for self-designed undergraduate curriculum course in international studies, 1969; University of Pittsburgh – Seoul University Relationships, 1969; Chinese Gazetteer data base project, 1969; establishment of training school for rural health personnel in Dahomey, West Africa, 1969; draft of by laws of Pennsylvania Council for international education, 1970.
- International Studies Center (UCIS), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)